Welcome to the first lecture in our
series on Bitcoin and cryptocurrencies.
I want to start by introducing the four
lecturers who are going to be speaking in
the series.
The first lecturer is Joseph Bonneau.
He's a post doctoral researcher in
computer science at Princeton University.
The second lecturer is me, Ed Felten.
I'm a professor at Princeton in computer
science, and in the Woodrow Wilson School.
The third lecturer is Arvind Narayanan.
He's a computer science
professor at Princeton.
And fourth, our special guest
lecturer is Andrew Miller.
He's a PhD student in computer
science at the University of Maryland.
There will be eleven lectures in total.
In this lecture number one,
we're going to do two things.
First, we'll introduce some cryptographic
primitives that turn out to
be necessary for
talking about cryptocurrencies.
In particular,
we'll talk about cryptographic hashes and
digital signatures.
And we'll talk about some of the ways
in which those are used to build
cryptocurrencies.
And then at the end of the lecture, we'll
start talking about cryptocurrencies.
And I'll give some examples
of simple cryptocurrencies.
That illustrate some of the design
challenges that we need to deal with.
I want to apologize for covering the
cryptographic material at the beginning.
Unfortunately we have to eat some
of our vegetables a little bit,
in order to lay groundwork for
the cryptocurrency stuff.
So if you came for the cryptocurrency
stuff let, me assure you first of all.
That we will get to it in this lecture.
And that having laid
the groundwork in this lecture.
There's going to be a lot more
specifically cryptocurrency-focused
material in later lectures.
All right, so let's get to it.